I am Gado.
我叫卡多
By collecting 99 keys,
永恒之枪组织
Gungnir plans to take over the world.
企图集齐99把钥匙 从而主宰世界
The one fighting against Gungnir and all that they stand for,
而敢于挑战永恒之枪和这个企图的人
is none other than The Guide's son, Teruasa Oda.
正是引领者的儿子织田照朝
With all of his friends' lives depending on it,
最终的对决左右着所有同伴的生死
the final battle continues.
现在最终对决仍在继续
The foolish humans
愚蠢的人类
struggle and suffer,
挣扎吧 受苦吧
shedding tears of blood.
流下血泪吧
Teruasa, accept your fate.
照朝 接受你的命运吧
Teruasa Oda, Guide,
织田照朝 引领者
you both have one word left.
你们都只剩一个词
The blue word is something that fits into a cube with sides one meter long.
蓝色石板的答案 可以装进边长为一米的立方体里
It's a person,
这是一个人
and Teruasa Oda has touched it.
并且织田照朝曾碰触过这个人
The person is deceased.
此人已逝世
The black word
黑色石板的答案
is edible,
它可以食用
and is in this room.
并且存在于这个房间里
It is not a living thing.
它没有生命
It did not exist before the birth of mankind.
在人类诞生以前 它不存在
It is not a tool.
它不是工具
It's possible to get it for less than 1,000 yen.
我们可以 按一千日元以下的价格买到它
The Guide still has three chances to consult with a friend.
引领者还有三次咨询同伴的机会
Teruasa Oda can only consult with a friend once more.
织田照朝只剩一次咨询同伴的机会
If The Guide guesses correctly this turn,
如果引领者在这一轮猜对
he will be the winner.
他将是游戏的胜者
I'm out of time.
我没有退路了
Forget a counterattack. If he guesses correctly now, I've lost.
就算我想要反击 如果他在这一轮猜对 我必输无疑
If that happens…
如果他赢的话…
All eight of us who participated in the tournament will be killed.
我们八个锦标赛参赛者都会被杀死
The only way to save everyone
如果想挽救大家的性命
is for Teruasa to win the game.
照朝必须赢
And as soon as the game ends,
而且游戏一结束
they're going to attack the G20 summit venue.
他们会进攻20国集团峰会的会场
If we let that happen, the world will fall into chaos.
如果让这种事发生 世界将陷入混乱
And a huge number of people will lose their lives.
无数人将会丧命
All of that pressure on Terurin's shoulders…
现在所有的压力都落在了小照照肩上
Don't give up!
千万不要认输
You have fought very bravely.
到目前为止 你表现得很优秀
I am proud of you.
我为你感到骄傲
Keep your opinions to yourself.
不要说这种话
I had respect for you when I was a child.
小时候我确实敬重你
But now…
但是现在…
I feel sorry for you, clinging pathetically to the keys.
看到你这么依赖钥匙 我为你感到可悲
I will use the keys to create a society free from conflict, and save thousands.
那些钥匙可以创建一个 没有冲突的社会 拯救无数人
You're wrong!
错了
The keys are just instruments from which desire is born.
那些钥匙是勾起欲望的工具
Something like that can't be used to save anyone.
那种东西救不了任何人
Wasn't it you who said we should save people from their desires?
你不是说过 要把人从欲望中拯救出来吗？
Have you forgotten?
你忘了吗？
When you first showed me the key…
你第一次给我看钥匙的时候…
It's desire that can never be satisfied.
欲壑难填
The flames of desire ignite conflict.
欲望的火焰会点燃冲突
It's written in history.
这已经写进历史里了
That's why, no matter how much luck you have, you shouldn't be greedy.
因此不论你有多幸运 你都不能贪婪
You mustn't obsess over getting what you want.
你不能沉迷于获取你想要的东西
Try to become someone who can save those
你试着成为一个拯救者吧
who become consumed by desire.
拯救被欲望吞噬的人
I wanted to become like you.
我以前想要成为像你一样的人
That's why after you were gone,
因此即使你离开了我
I always tried to follow in your footsteps.
我依然努力追随你的脚步
Even when I got caught up in the civil war in Africa,
当我在非洲被卷入内战时
or when I escaped with captives in South America,
当我在南美和俘虏一起逃生时
I thought desperately, "What would you do?"
我心想 如果是你的话 定会拼命思考如何不抛弃身边的人
Trying my best to save those around me.
我一直以来也是这样做的
That's why Teruasa
所以照朝君
tried to save Maruko.
才会想要拯救丸子
Will you quit?
你会停手吗？
It's foolish to risk your life dancing with the devil.
冒着生命危险与恶魔共舞很愚蠢
That's not the only time.
不止是那一次
When he fought Hyodo…
他和兵头对决时也是如此
What you really want
你真正想要的
is to be in the spotlight again.
是重新回到聚光灯下
If that's so, then you don't need the key.
如果是那样 你并不需要恶魔钥匙
You can achieve it by effort alone.
你光凭努力也能做得到
Don't give in to desire!
不要屈服于欲望
Terurin got his excessive sense of justice
小照照身上强烈的正义感
from his dad?
是遗传于他的爸爸吗？
Whatever danger awaits,
无论前方有什么危险
I will crush Gungnir's ambitions.
我都会摧毁永恒之枪的企图
That's what saved me too.
他也拯救了我
You're a tough player.
你很强大
The power to win was already in you.
你自己已经拥有获胜的能力
Don't you remember what you said to me
你在露营那晚对我说的话
that night we went camping?
你忘记了吗？
I remember very well, even now.
我直到现在依然记得一清二楚
Then what is all this for?
那这一切算什么？
You're going to kill a lot of people.
你将会夺走无数人的生命
Then let me ask you.
那我问你
Do you think you are innocent?
你以为自己完全清白吗？
You also took a life when you first played ACMA:GAME.
你第一次玩ACMA：GAME游戏时 就害死了一个人
I knew that man too.
那个人的事我也知情
That man
那小子
had his life taken by Gado.
因为输给你 被卡多夺走了性命
Deceased.
他在生前是你认识的人
I want to make a guess.
我要回答
Then, Guide, go ahead.
那么引领者 说出答案
The correct answer is
蓝色石板的答案是
the head of the Maruko family,
丸子家族的少主
Mitsuhide Maruko.
丸子光秀
If I lose, you can kill me on the spot.
如果我输了 你可以当场杀了我
I accept your guess.
我接受你的回答
The answer is…
答案…
INCORRECT
（不正确）
…incorrect!
…不正确
The Guide was wrong?
引领者大人猜错了？
Maruko's name came to mind first.
我确实最先想到了丸子的名字
But that's not what I wrote.
但是我没有写下来
I knew that was a name you'd reach eventually.
因为我知道你一定会猜到这个名字
He's not invincible after all.
太好了 他也不是无敌的
One more chance.
又多了一次机会
Guide, why not use a doll?
引领者大人 为何不使用人偶？
I don't need to.
我不需要
-But-- -Don't overstep.
-但是… -不要多言
Forgive me.
是我失礼了
Now's my chance to counterattack.
这是个反击的机会
It won't open!
开不了
It must be an enclosed space.
这可能是个封闭空间
Can Oda stop The Guide alone?
织田一个人能阻止引领者吗？
I'd rather he doesn't.
阻止不了又有什么关系？
If The Guide wins, everyone's going to die!
如果引领者赢了 大家都得死
But it will shake up the world.
但是世界会翻天覆地
It's going to be a historical moment.
历史性的时刻将会到来
Isn't it exciting?
这不刺激吗？
Ouch.
好痛
Pain is proof you're alive.
痛证明你还活着
You should be thankful.
你就心存感激吧
Oda,
织田
we're counting on you.
一定要加油
Then it's your turn,
现在交换次序
Teruasa Oda.
织田照朝
Choose whether to ask a question or make a guess.
选择要回答还是提问
Okay.
好
The black word
黑色石板的答案
is something that didn't exist before mankind,
在人类诞生以前不存在
so it must be a food created by humans.
也就是说 它是人类制作的食物
And you can get it for less than 1,000 yen,
我们可以 按一千日元以下的价格买到它
and it's in this room.
它在这个房间里
There's one thing in this room that fits those conditions.
在这个房间里 有一个东西符合这些条件
But I can't be 100% sure.
但我不能百分百确定
Should I consult with Ui and the others?
我要咨询初和其他人吗？
Or save my last doll, and make my own guess?
还是保留最后一个人偶 先自己猜？
What should I do?
我要怎么做？
By the way,
话说回来
I came here to play the game, but also to separate you from your past.
我来这里除了玩游戏外 还为了让你告别过去
First, you lost a memory of your mother.
首先是让你失去关于你妈妈的记忆
Next, a memory of me.
其次是让你失去关于我的记忆
If there is anything worthy of a final farewell,
如果要问什么最适合作为最后的告别
what better than…
那就是
the lives of your friends.
他们的性命
All of them
他们几个
risked their lives to be here.
冒着生命危险来到这里
I just need to win.
我只需要赢就行了
Gado, I want to make a guess.
卡多 我要回答
Then, let's hear it.
那么织田照朝 说出你的答案
The black stone slab is
黑色石板的答案是
herbal tea.
草药茶
The answer is…
回答…
incorrect!
错误
No.
糟糕
I was wrong.
猜错了
What a pity to fail at such a critical moment.
在这么关键的时候猜错 真遗憾啊
Then the turn goes to the other player.
那么交换次序
Guide, choose whether to answer or guess.
引领者 选择要回答还是提问
Do you feel as though you've been pushed into an abyss?
你是不是感觉自己被推进了深渊？
How are you going to get out?
你要如何突破困局？
Or maybe better to give up.
还是说你要放弃？
Even in an abyss,
即使在深渊里
miracles can happen.
也有可能发生奇迹
As long as you don't give up,
只要不放弃
there is always a ray of light.
就一定能找到希望的光
Miracles?
奇迹？
I too believed in such things long ago.
我曾经也相信那种东西
To restore this filthy world,
为了重建这个肮脏的世界
first, I hunted down the key owners.
我开始寻找钥匙持有者
Instead of fighting, I asked for cooperation.
我不是要与他们战斗 而是想寻求合作
I taught them how to use the keys,
我教他们如何使用钥匙
and persuaded them to join me.
然后说服他们与我联手
But…
但是…
once they realized the power of the keys,
当他们知晓钥匙的魔力后
they were consumed by desire, and began to fight.
都被欲望吞噬了 并开始互相争斗
Not only that, but I became the target of their desires.
不仅如此 我也成了他们满足私欲的目标
They wanted my company's fortune and management rights,
他们要夺走公司的资产和经营权
and even my family's lives.
甚至还要夺走我家人的性命
So your death…
所以你才会假死…
Chairman Oda!
会长
Dad! Dad!
爸爸
That's why
所以
I decided to end my life as Seiji Oda.
我决定结束织田清司的人生
After that, I tried to find people to join me, by searching for key owners,
在那之后 我开始寻找钥匙持有者 想要借此寻找志同道合的人
but there was not a single person
但是没有一个人
who agreed with my noble ideals.
认同我的崇高理念
My faith in humanity dimmed,
我对人类的期待已经消失殆尽
and all that was left was despair.
最后剩下的只有绝望
And so I decided
后来我开始醒悟
that I would take the lead
我要带头
and guide people in the right direction.
引领人们走向正确的方向
The Guide was born in that moment.
在那一刻 引领者大人诞生了
To prepare for a new world,
为了准备迎接新世界
I brought together successful people from different fields to create Gungnir.
我集合了各领域的杰出人士 创立了永恒之枪组织
All that time…
在那期间…
you never once considered destroying the keys?
你一次都没想过要摧毁钥匙吗？
Destroy them?
摧毁？
You've seen it all.
你自己也亲眼见证了很多次
The ugliness the keys bring out in people.
那些钥匙会激起持有者丑恶的一面
You didn't think a world without the keys would be a better place?
你难道没有想过 将钥匙摧毁殆尽后的世界会更好吗？
There is no point trying to get rid of the keys.
摧毁钥匙没有意义
What do you mean?
什么意思？
A devil's key can never be destroyed.
恶魔钥匙永远无法摧毁
They can't be destroyed?
无法摧毁？
Exactly.
没错
It is not possible to eradicate them from this world.
让钥匙在世界上消失是不可能的
Even if the owner of a key dies,
如果钥匙持有者死了
the key is simply returned to us.
钥匙会回到我们手上
Then we allow the key to fall in front of another.
然后我们会将钥匙落到其他人面前
It is done at random.
而且这是随机的
And so the history of conflict repeats itself once more.
所以人类纷争的历史 会一次又一次重演
Teruasa, don't be fooled.
照朝 别被他骗了
What?
你说什么？
Devils have long been known for deceiving people.
自古以来 恶魔把人骗得团团转
If you take him seriously, he will only crush your beliefs.
如果你把它的话当真 它会摧毁你的信念
Guide?
引领者？
I'll ask a question.
我要提问
What?
什么？
He's not making a guess?
他不回答吗？
That's unusually cautious for him.
他还真是出奇的谨慎啊
He must be after something.
他一定有什么目的
Is the blue word a name from the past?
蓝色石板词是一个旧名吗？
Now for the answer.
答案…
Yes.
正确
Has he figured it out?
他猜到答案了吗？
If I don't guess correctly now, he'll win the game next turn.
如果我这一次猜错 他下一轮就赢定了
A boat?
有船？
Yes.
对
Seems that Asai found a boat around here before.
浅井似乎曾在这附近发现过一艘船
Can we use it to get off the island?
我们可以划船离开小岛吗？
No.
不行
But the boat The Guide arrived on must be somewhere.
但引领者乘的船一定藏在某个地方
They're coming this way.
有人过来了
Then the turn goes to the next player.
现在交换次序
Teruasa Oda,
织田照朝
will you guess or ask a question?
你要回答还是提问？
Teruasa.
照朝
Gado, I want to use a doll.
卡多 我要使用人偶
Good,
可以
the last doll.
最后一个人偶
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
You need to carry this burden alone.
不要一个人硬扛
You trusted your father all this time, and now you have to fight him.
你一直这么信任你父亲 现在却要和他决战
It must be overwhelming.
这一定让你感到茫然失措
He'll try to use it against you by psyching you out.
而且他可能会利用这一点 在精神上压垮你
But, Teruasa…
但是照朝…
you're not alone.
你不是一个人
We might not be able to do anything,
我们也许做不了什么
but we are here by your side.
但会陪在你身边
Ui.
初
Do you remember this?
你记得这个吗？
You still have it?
你还留着？
The wallet they stole from me in middle school.
这是我上中学时 被他们抢走的钱包
It was you who got it back, wasn't it?
是你帮我要回来的 对吧？
I--
当我…
When I saw it on my desk,
看到钱包躺在我的课桌上时
I was so happy.
我高兴得不得了
What happened to your face?
你的脸怎么了？
Fell over in soccer.
踢足球的时候摔倒了
I knew I had someone by my side who was looking out for me.
因为我知道有个人在身边守护着我
That's why I've come this far.
所以我才能走这么远
This time I'm looking out for you.
这一次该轮到我守护你了
No matter how this ends, I have no regrets.
不管结果如何 我都不后悔
I'm just happy…
能和你这样再次见面
that I got to see you again.
真的太好了
Ui.
初
You've always been an important friend to me.
你一直都是我最重要的朋友
You looked up to me,
你敬重我
thinking of me as your competition.
把我当做竞争对手
To tell you the truth,
其实
I thought the same about you.
我和你想的一样
So when you said you wanted to fight me,
当你跟我说要与我战斗时
I was happy.
我也很开心
I'm going to defeat you.
我会打败你
I'm glad I got to see you again too.
我也很开心能再次见到你
Teruasa.
照朝君
Yuki.
悠季
It's been amazing
我也很高兴
to see your happy face again.
看到你容光焕发的面庞
I owe that happiness to you.
那是因为你给了我力量
You…
你总是…
Gonna be an A.I. developer?
你要当人工智能开发者吗？
…were always smiling by our side.
…在我们身边微笑着
You're so kind.
你非常善良
Ui and I
初和我
thought that we had to protect you.
都觉得要好好保护你
But it was your kindness that protected me.
但实际上是你的善良一直在保护我
Thank you.
谢谢
Teruasa.
照朝
You're pleased you met me too, right?
你见到我也很高兴吧？
Of course.
对 很高兴
I'm a stronger person, thanks to you.
谢谢你让我变得更坚强了
I know the real Yukari.
我知道真正的你是什么样的
Your strength saved me many times.
你的坚强帮助了我很多次
-Jump! -What?
-快跳 -什么？
Thank you for fighting with me.
谢谢和我一起战斗
You reassured me.
你让我感到很踏实
If you win, you can come and see my show.
如果你赢了 我请你去看我的演出
I want you to see
我要让你看看
how I shine on stage.
在舞台上闪闪发光的我
You really did
你真的
make this a fun ride, right to the end.
在这个有趣的旅程中 成功走到了最后
I've played countless guys at gambling in my life,
到目前为止 我在赌博中和很多人交过手
but this is the first time I've been tense just watching a game.
但这是我第一次 光是看比赛就紧张得不得了
It sucks, huh?
真烦人啊 对吧？
I went to the trouble of betting on you,
我好不容易把赌注押在你身上
and looks like you're gonna lose.
结果你现在好像要输了
Senya.
潜夜
You beat me once.
你赢过我一次
How wonderful it feels!
好开心啊
You were the best opponent ever.
你是最棒的对手哦
Our game isn't over yet.
我们的比赛还未结束
There's still something we can do.
一定还有我们能做的事
But you're by my side now.
但现在你成了我的伙伴
This gamble I've got to win.
这场赌博 我一定要赢
We didn't follow you because we thought you were going to win,
我们跟随你 不是因为我们认为你会赢
but because we knew we wouldn't regret
而是因为我们知道 无论结果如何
whatever outcome you achieved.
我们都不会后悔
Teruasa,
照朝
are you still unsure?
现在还是没有信心吗？
No.
不
Now I'm confident.
现在我信心十足
Then go get it.
那就上吧
Gado,
卡多
I'll make a guess.
我要回答
Please go ahead.
那么织田照朝 说出你的答案
Guide,
引领者
you can't help but win with a flourish.
你执着于获得压倒性的胜利
So the answer
所以你一定选了
must be something obvious.
十分显而易见的答案
Such as…
比如…
the liquid you injected right in front of me.
你在游戏开始时 当着我的面注射的
If it's a drug,
如果答案是药物
it's not a living thing or a tool.
那么它既没有生命 也不是工具
Also, it's not usually available for sale.
这样的药物通常不出售
I'm sure I've heard it costs less than 100 yen.
但我确信我听说过 它的成本不到一百日元
So it's possible to get it for under 1,000 yen.
所以我们可以 按一千日元以下的价格买到它
Since it's injected into the bloodstream,
另外 既然它可以注射到血管中
it must be safe to enter the stomach.
那么它进入到人的胃里也一定没问题
In other words, it's edible.
换句话说 它可以食用
The word on the black stone slate is
黑色石板的答案是
Theobrom.
可可碱
I accept your guess.
我接受你的答案
The answer is…
回答…
THEOBROM
（可可碱）
Correct.
正确
He did it!
太好了
He got it.
猜对了
All three! All three!
三个词都猜对了
Now we stand a chance.
现在机会来了
If The Guide misses the next one…
如果引领者在下一轮猜错就赢了
You finally realized that the drug counted as something edible.
你终于注意到 那是可以吃的东西了？
It took you even longer than I thought.
这比我想象的要久啊
Guide.
引领者
Teruasa Oda has three correct answers,
织田照朝猜对了三个词
so if you guess incorrectly, you will lose.
所以接下来如果你猜错的话 那你就输了
That's not going to happen.
那种事不会发生
I'm certain my answer is correct.
我一定能猜对
Then, Guide,
那么引领者
do you want to ask a question, or make a guess?
你要提问还是回答？
Since it took a lot to get here, shall I use a doll before I answer?
好不容易比到了现在 在回答之前 我先使用一个人偶吧
You wish to consult?
你想要咨询？
Very good.
没问题
Get me a glass of water.
给我拿一杯水
What? He's just taking a break?
什么？他只是休息而已吗？
Jeez. Why's he always gotta be so cocky?
哎呦 他怎么总是这么从容？
Guide.
引领者大人
I told you not to speak out of turn.
我说过不要多言
It's not that I don't trust you,
我不是不信任您
but we must avoid closing the path
但我们必须尽一切可能
to a world without conflict at all costs.
避免封闭通往无冲突世界的道路
You don't care what happens to this world.
你根本不关心这个世界会变成什么样
You just want to take my key.
你只想得到我的钥匙
So you'll obey me.
因此你才会臣服于我
As you wish.
那就按您的意思来办
Someone's coming.
有人过来了
Wait, it's not what you think.
等等 不要误会
I'm Mori. Akira Mori.
我是毛利 毛利明
The Dragon King Mori?
毛利龙王？
Are you here playing a game?
莫非你也是来这里参赛的？
Yes.
对
Do you know about the tournament?
你也知道锦标赛的事？
I heard about it from Teruasa.
不久之前 我听照朝说过
Oda?
你是说织田吗？
The Guide, or Gungnir's leader, is planning something terrible?
引领者或永恒之枪的领袖 在策划什么阴谋吗？
Yes.
对
The true identity of The Guide is Teruasa Oda's father.
引领者的真实身份 是织田照朝的父亲
What?
什么？
Why did you change?
你为什么变了？
No matter how I try,
无论如何
I can't believe you are the same man as the Seiji Oda I knew.
我都没法相信 你是我认识的那个织田清司
Why do you think the chairman of a trading company
你觉得一个贸易公司的经营者
would fake his own death
为什么要假死
and become obsessed with a world free from conflict?
然后执着于打造一个 没有冲突的世界？
I started this because of your mother.
这一切的起因是你妈妈
Mom?
妈妈？
It was your eleventh birthday.
在你11岁生日那天
She died in a traffic accident when traveling in Brussels.
她在布鲁塞尔旅游时 因为交通事故身亡了
It's okay to cry if you need to.
想哭就哭吧 照朝
Mom will be sad if I cry.
我哭的话 妈妈会难过的
But that's not the whole truth.
但那不是事情的真相
Now you're telling lies just to get to me?
你觉得这种谎话能动摇我吗？
That rainy day in Brussels,
那天布鲁塞尔下着雨
an ambassador from the Republic of Miravelia was targeted.
一伙恐怖分子 要袭击米拉维利亚共和国的大使
Your mother was killed in the attack.
你妈妈被卷进了这场袭击中
Take cover! Move, move, move!
这边 在这里找掩护
TO TERUASA HAPPY 11TH BIRTHDAY
（祝照朝11岁生日快乐）
WISHING YOU A FUTURE FILLED WITH HAPPINESS
（祝你未来的人生幸福满满）
Impossible.
不可能
Of course, you wouldn't know.
你不知道真相也很正常
At the time, Japan was set to provide several tens of billions of yen
那时候日本决定 向饱受战争摧残的米拉维利亚共和国
in humanitarian aid to the war-torn Republic of Miravelia.
提供数百亿日元的人道主义援助
At that moment…
在那种关头…
if it came out that a Japanese citizen had lost her life due to terrorism,
如果日本人 因为恐怖袭击而丧命的事被公开
it would impact the decision to provide aid.
人道主义援助会受影响
And so…
所以…
the terrorist attack was covered up.
恐怖袭击的事被压下去了
I found out
这个真相
after I became the owner of a key.
是我在成为钥匙持有者之后发现的
It was right after the day you and I went camping.
就在我和你一起去露营之后
Your mother
你妈妈
was killed by a world that continues to start ugly conflicts.
被不断滋生丑恶冲突的世界害死了
You must understand.
你应该明白
Originally, this tournament was for you,
这个锦标赛在一开始
to put your strength to the test.
就是为了测试你的能力而举办的
For me?
为我举办？
It was designed to challenge you.
目的是为了考验你
And so…
所以…
I put you up against those who are closest to you.
我才会让你跟最亲近的人对战
As I hoped, you came out on top
如我所料 你出色地胜出了
and found your way back to me.
并来到了我的身边
I don't believe that was chance…
这不是偶然
but fate.
而是命运
Teruasa…
照朝…
you're ready.
你已经准备好了
Join me.
和我一起战斗吧
Let's restore this world together.
我们一起重建这个世界
I can't do that.
不行
I'm going to win this game
我要赢下这个比赛
and destroy every last key.
把钥匙全部摧毁
And…
然后…
I'm going to rescue you from the key's spell.
我会把你从钥匙的诅咒中解救出来
Looks like I have no choice but to finish this.
看来我只能做个了结了
Bring glory to Gungnir.
为永恒之枪带来荣耀吧
Gado, I'll make a guess.
卡多 我要回答
Guide, go ahead.
引领者 说出你的答案
The blue word is a human Teruasa has touched.
蓝色石板的答案是照朝碰触过的人
A deceased person.
这个人已经离世
A name from the past.
这是个旧名
The correct answer is…
蓝色石板的答案是…
Reika Oda's maiden name,
织田丽华的旧名
Reika Yamamoto.
山本丽华
I accept your guess.
我接受你的答案
The answer is…
回答…
incorrect!
不正确
The winner of Word Investigation is
“三词问查”的胜者是
Teruasa Oda!
织田照朝
We won.
我们赢了
We did it, we won!
太好了 我们赢了
Unbelievable.
不可能
Guide,
引领者
I beat you.
我打败你了
Time to settle the bets.
现在清算赌注
Once the enclosed space is opened,
封闭空间被解除后
first the loser will hand over all of his keys to the winner.
首先 败者要将自己持有的钥匙 全部交给胜者
What the hell?
怎么可以？
Next, as demanded by Teruasa Oda,
其次 根据织田照朝的要求
The Guide will bring Gungnir to an end.
引领者要解散永恒之枪
A world free from conflict
没有冲突的世界
is what I want too.
也是我想要的世界
So,
所以
I don't deny your ideals.
我并没有否定你的理想
Humans thrive
人类的繁荣
by following their desires,
源自于人们对欲望的追求
but at the same time,
但与此同时
they engage in ugly conflicts to satisfy such cravings.
他们也会为了满足欲望 陷入到丑恶的冲突中
The devil's key is a forbidden tool
而勾起这种欲望的就是恶魔钥匙
that stirs up man's desires.
它们是禁忌的工具
Something like that won't save anyone.
那样的东西拯救不了人类
If you really were The Guide, leader of mankind,
如果你真的是人类的引领者
you wouldn't have been defeated.
就不应该被我打败
Isn't that right?
对吗？
That may be so.
也许是吧
Wait! Guide--
等等 引领者大人…
That's enough.
够了
Gungnir is over.
永恒之枪解散了
What a showdown between father and son.
真是一场精彩的父子对决啊
I thoroughly enjoyed myself.
我看得无比享受
Guide.
引领者
Since you no longer have a key, this will be my final goodbye.
既然你已经没了钥匙 这应该是我们最后一次见面了
Teruasa Oda,
织田照朝
I look forward to seeing you again.
期待下次见面
Wait.
等等
Gado…
卡多…
I have no intention of meeting you again.
我不想再见到你
What's that supposed to mean?
你说什么？
I told you, you can't completely destroy the keys.
我说过 你无法彻底摧毁钥匙
Don't expect me to believe the words of a devil.
你以为我会完全听信恶魔说的话吗？
Whatever you say is impossible
当你说不可能时
is likely the opposite.
真相也许就是可能
I…
我…
will find a way to destroy all of the keys.
一定会找到摧毁所有钥匙的办法
If you can find a way,
你要是能找的话
be my guest.
那就找吧
I'm sure we will meet again.
我们一定还会再见面的
Guide!
引领者大人
It's over.
消失了
Teruasa…
照朝…
Wow, fancy!
好厉害
It's open!
打开了
Oda.
织田
-Mori, are you okay? -Yes.
-毛利 你们还好吗？ -还好
Who won? The Guide?
谁赢了？是引领者吗？
Teruasa would never lose.
照朝怎么可能会输
Thank god! He saved us!
太好了 得救了
Teruasa!
照朝
Ryukan!
龙肝先生
Hyodo, you all came too.
兵头 你们也来了
Okamoto.
冈本
You look well.
你看上去很精神
It's been a long time.
久未问候
I'm not sure what I should call you.
不知道该怎么称呼你
Hyodo-chin, been a while.
小兵兵 好久不见
You're here too?
你也在？
What? Got a problem?
怎么？不行吗？
Hoshin!
崩心
Don't move!
不准动
This time I'll aim for the head.
这次我瞄准的是头部
What are you trying to do?
你想做什么？
I should be asking you that.
我倒想问 你想做什么？
After ten long years,
我们筹谋了十多年
just when I thought we could finally collect all 99 keys,
就在我以为能集齐99把钥匙的时候
you decide to put on a display of fatherly affection
你却给我们表演无聊的父子情
and hand them all over to your son?
最后还把钥匙全交给你的儿子？
Don't make me laugh!
开什么玩笑
Give it up.
你放弃吧
They were never your keys to have.
那些从来都不是你的钥匙
Yes.
是啊
That's why you're no use to me now.
所以你现在对我没用处了
Look out!
当心
Are you okay?
没事吧？
Hey! Hey!
喂
What have you done?
你干什么？
Why?
为什么？
Why you?
为什么是你？
It's going to collapse!
这里要塌了
Everyone, get out of here!
大家快逃出去
Ui!
初
Quickly!
快点
-We're going to die! -Go!
-我们要死了 -快
-Run! -Teruasa!
-跑 -照朝
-Yuki! Quickly! -No! No!
-悠季 快 -不
-Teruasa! -Quickly!
-照朝 -快
Hurry! Hurry!
快点
Teruasa,
照朝
what was the last word you wrote down?
你写的最后一个词是什么？
Forget it, let's go!
别管了 快走
Was it me?
是我吗？
SEIJI ODA
（织田清司）
Yes.
对
The Seiji Oda I knew died 13 years ago.
我敬重的织田清司在13年前就死了
Go to Miteratert.
去米特拉特
The devil's keys.
把恶魔钥匙
Extinguish them.
清除…
Please.
拜托了
My son.
儿子
Dad!
爸爸
-We need to go! -Dad!
-不要去 -爸爸
-There's no time!
-没时间了
Teruasa!
照朝
Come and try this.
快过来尝尝
Wow, it's yummy.
真好吃
You like it!
太好了
Hey! He said it's yummy.
喂 他说好吃
That's right,
这款巧克力
your mom designed that with the food department.
是你妈妈和我们食品部一起研发的
Think it'll sell?
你觉得它会大卖吗？
Then can I join the company and figure out how to sell stuff?
那我能加入爸爸的公司 研究怎么让它畅销吗？
You want to do what your dad does?
你想继承爸爸的事业？
I wonder if I can.
不知道我能不能行
I'm sure of it.
你一定能行
If you keep working hard.
只要继续努力就能行
You've grown up.
你真的长大了
One week has passed since the ACMA:GAME tournament.
现在距ACMA：GAME锦标赛结束 已经过去一周了
No one suspects that they were about to lose their lives in an attack,
没有人知道 他们差点被卷入冲突中 并因此丧命
and the world goes on as usual.
这个世界照常运行着
Like nothing happened.
好像什么都没有发生过
No one knows what occurred on that island.
没人知道那个岛上发生的事
Not a word was announced about The Guide or Gungnir.
关于引领者或永恒之枪 社会上没有公开任何信息
We searched the island,
我们搜索了那个岛
but Hoshin was nowhere to be found.
但没有找到崩心
He escaped.
他逃走了
Ryukan invited me to join Oda Group,
龙肝先生邀请我加入织田集团
but I refused.
但我拒绝了
There's still something I need to do.
我还有未完成的事
Did you hear? The fans are going to vote for who takes lead vocals.
听说了吗？ 这次的主唱由粉丝投票决定
What? Isn't it me?
不是我吗？
Yukari, how many shows did you miss?
紫 你错过了多少演出？
Management was furious.
运营都气疯了
You didn't even pick up the phone. What were you doing?
连电话都不接 你干什么去了？
I guess I was growing up.
我猜
DRAGON KING AKIRA MORI VS NEWCOMER AI OROCHI
（龙王毛利明 对战最新人工智能大蛇）
As a player who rarely appears before the media,
毛利棋手 以前您很少出现在媒体面前
what circumstances led to you taking on a game against AI?
是什么情况促使您 与人工智能对弈？
One of my previous opponents is Manabe,
在一场游戏中 我和真锅对战
the developer of OROCHI.
而她开发了大蛇
Yuki!
悠季
Relax.
放轻松
Got it.
好的
Breathe.
呼气
That's the spirit!
这就对了
Teruasa's not answering?
照朝还是没接电话吗？
I know.
对
It's only the biggest show of a lifetime for you and OROCHI.
那家伙真是的 这可是你和大蛇难得一遇的大舞台
What the hell is he doing?
他到底干什么去了？
Do you think he's searching for keys?
他不会是去寻找钥匙了吧？
We told him we'd help him. He wouldn't go alone.
我们跟他说过会帮他一起找 让他不要单独行动
Don't worry. He'll be here.
别担心 他会来的
OROCHI, locate Teruasa's key, just in case.
大蛇 以防万一 快定位照朝的钥匙
Roger that.
收到
Let's see.
我看看
Looks like the keys are hidden where they should be.
钥匙似乎藏在那个隐秘的地方
Wait, there's one key outside the room.
等等 有一把钥匙在房间外
What?
什么？
Ui, Yuki,
初 悠季
what are you looking at?
你们在看什么？
Teruasa's key is abroad for some reason.
不知为何 照朝的钥匙竟然会显示在国外
-Cambodia?
-柬埔寨？
CAMBODIA
（柬埔寨）
MITERATERT RUINS
（米特拉特遗迹）
Collect all 99 keys and end it all.
集齐99把钥匙 然后结束一切
My father's dying wish falls to me.
我继承了父亲的遗志
Terurin,
小照照
I couldn't help joining.
我来了
Senya, how did you get here?
你怎么来了？
You're here to collect the keys, right?
你来这里收集钥匙 对吧？
You went off by yourself again.
你又一个人行动了
Ui-ui and the others will be angry.
初和其他人会生气的哦
I'm doing this alone.
我要自己解决
I know the names of the winners of the tournaments that took place abroad.
我知道海外锦标赛冠军的名字
You may have done your research,
你应该调查了吧？
but so did I.
我也做了调查哦
So…
那么
where do we go from here?
下一站要去哪里呢？
Good question.
是啊
Our first stop…
第一站是…